All right. So, we have two tasks to complete,
好的为了定义更高效的 Word2Vec skip-gram 模型
to define a more efficient Word2vec skip-gram model.
我们需要完成两项任务
Here, I'm calling this model skip-gram neg to include negative sampling.
我将这个模型称为 SkipGramNeg 表示包含负采样功能
This model takes in our usual vocab and embedding dimension.
参数包括词汇表和嵌入维度
It also takes in a noise distribution, if it's provided.
还包括噪点分布的参数
Okay. So, first, we want to define two embedding layers,
Ok首先 我们需要定义两个嵌入层
one for input and one for output words.
一个针对输入字词 一个针对输出字词
Here, I'm calling those in_embed and out_embed.
称之为 in_embed 和 out_embed
I want you to define these layers,
请定义这两个层级
such that they can accept an input or output target as input
它们会接受输入或输出目标
and return an embedding that's a vector of dimension in_embed.
并返回一个维度为 n_embed 的嵌入向量
I'll also suggest that you initialize the weights of these layers
建议使用范围是 -1 - 1 的均匀分布
using a uniform distribution between negative one and one.
来初始化这些层级的权重
Now, let's look at our loss function for a moment.
我们来看看损失函数
When we think about defining a negative sampling loss,
在定义负采样损失时
we know that this loss will take in a few things as input.
这个损失将接受几个输入参数
It will for sure take in our input word embedding, vwi.
肯定会接受输入字词嵌入 vwi
It will also take in our correct output word embedding
还会接受正确输出字词嵌入 uw0
uw0 and several noisy incorrect embeddings uwi.
以及几个错误嵌入 uwi
So, in this model definition,
你需要在模型定义部分
I'm actually going to ask you to define
定义三个不同的 forward 函数
three different forward functions for creating these embeddings.
从而创建这些嵌入
The first forward input should return our input embeddings,
第一个 forward_input 应该返回输入嵌入
which are just going to be our input words passed through our input embedding layer.
即经过输入嵌入层的输入字词
Similarly, forward output, which should return
然后是 forward_output 函数
output vectors for passed and output words.
它应该返回传入的输出字词的输出向量
Finally, a forward noise function, this one is special.
最后是 forward_noise 函数 它比较特殊
It takes in a batch size and a number of
它的参数包括批次大小
noise samples to generate for performing negative sampling.
以及进行负采样的噪点样本数量
This function first gets noisy samples from a passed in noise distribution.
此函数首先从传入的噪点分布中获取噪点样本
If no distribution is passed in,
如果没有传入分布
this will default to uniform distribution.
则默认为均匀分布
Now, it gets a sample of noise words using
使用 torch.multinomial 获取噪点字词样本
torch.multinomial and gets batch size times n_samples of values.
并获得 batch_size*n_samples 个值
In this line, those words are being moved to a GPU, if available,
这行代码将字词移到 GPU 上（如果有 GPU 的话）
and what you need to do to complete this function is pass these words
要完成这个函数 你需要将这些字词
through the output embedding layer to get their respective embeddings.
传入输出嵌入层并获得相应的嵌入
So, you get our noise embeddings and then you should
获得噪点嵌入后
reshape these embeddings to be batch size by n_samples,
应该将这些嵌入变形为
by n_embed in dimension. All right.
(batch_size, n_samples, n_embed) 的维度
So, complete these forward functions,
好的 请完成这些 forward 函数
making sure to return correct embeddings for each forward function.
使每个 forward 函数都返回正确的嵌入
If you've completed this implementation,
完成这道练习后
you should be able to proceed with training this model.
就可以继续训练模型了
Next, I'll go over one solution for this model and I'll
接下来我将介绍我的实现方式
show you how I defined a custom negative sampling loss.
并演示我是如何定义自定义负采样损失的